Yaker, Edward Collection of Cooperative Housing Materials 6377
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Edward Yaker Collection of Cooperative Housing Materials
1996-2006
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Yaker, Edward
Amalgamated Housing Cooperative
Coordinating Council of Cooperatives
6377
1.22 cubic feet
1.1 linear ft.
Reports, publications, correspondence, recordss.
8447814
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183> kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, April 17, 2014
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, May 05, 2015
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Cooperative Community Bulletin; Cooperative Village Bulletin; Co-Op Highlights; Co-Op Community News; Yaker, Edward; Amalgamated Life Insurance; Delancey Crossing; East River Housing Corporation; Fedele Foods Development; Grand Street Consumers Cooperative; Lower Eastside Neighborhood Association (LENA); Marco Counsulting Group; National Rural Electric Cooperative Association (NRECA); New Roc Associates; New York City Economic Development Corporation; United Housing Foundation
8447814
- Coordinating Council of Cooperatives 30th Anniversary Celebration, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  June 5, 1996. Program booklet.
- Coordinating Council of Cooperatives 40th Anniversary Celebration, 2006 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  October 24, 2006. Program booklet
- Story of a Co-op Community: The First 75 Years, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Published history
- Grand Street Consumers Cooperative Annual Reports, 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- East River Housing Corporation Annual Reports, 1958-1963 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Cooperative Community Bulletin, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  v.1:no.1 (1956:Mar.) - v.2:no.8 (1958:Apr.). 15 issues, severral issues missing.
- Cooperative Village Bulletin, 1958-1962 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  v.2:no.9 (1958:June) - v.4:no.7 (1962:Jan.). 19 issues, several issues missing.
- Co-Op Highlights, 1958-1964 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  v.6:no.7 (1958:Sep.) - v.20:no.5 (1964:Oct.). 15 issues, severral issues missing.
- Co-Op Community News, 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  v.1:no.2 (1963:June) - v.6:no.1 (1965:Feb/Mar.). 9 issues, severral issues missing.
- Your Grand Street Consumer Co-Op (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Undated flyer
- Lower Eastside Neighborhood Association (LENA) (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Restated United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  September 30, 1999.
- Restated United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  Custodial Verification Report, 2nd Quarter, 1999.
- Restated United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  June 30, 1999.
- Restated United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  Custodial Verification Report, 1st Quarter, 1999.
- Restated United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  March 31, 1999.
- Restated United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Custodial Verification Report, 4th Quarter, 1998.
- Restated United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  December 31, 1998.
- Restated United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  March 31, 1998.
- Restated United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  Custodial Verification Report, 4th Quarter, 1997.
- Restated United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  December 31, 1997.
- Restated United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  March 1997. Actuarial Valuation as of January 1, 1996.
- Restated United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  December 31, 1996.
- United Housing Foundation and Subsidiary, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  April 8, 1997. Consolidated Financial Statements and Supplemental Materials for Years Ended December 31, 1996 and 1995
- Restated United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, 1998 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  May 12, 1998. Consolidated Financial Statements and Supplemental Materials for Years Ended December 31, 1997 and 1996
- Restated United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  April 14, 1999. Financial Statements for Years Ended December 31, 1998 and 1997
- Restated United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  Accounting Period June 1, 1999 through June 30, 1999.
- Executive Summary 1996 Proxy Report (Box 1, Folder 28)
  The Marco Consulting Group
- Grand Street Senior Houses, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  A United Housing Foundation Proposal to the New York City Economic Development Corporation in Conjunction with Delancey Crossing, a New Roc Associates and Fedele Foods Development Poject.
- Delancey Crossing, 1999 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  A New Roc Associates and Fedele Foods Development Project response to the RFP for the Delancey/Grand Street assisted living proposal.
- East River Housing Corporation Income Tax Deductions, 1957-1963 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  Deductions for 1957 and 1963, only.
- "The Consumer Awakens" Meeting Agenda, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  December 3, 1960. Speakers: Richard A. Montgomery, Ruth C. Deabler, james Mendenhall, Sidney Margolius, Ralph Reuter, Persia Campbell.
- Restated United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, 1995-1997 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  Contributions owed to Amalgamated Life Insurance.
- United Housing Foundation Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1996 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  Minutes from the Combined Special Meetings of the Board of Directors of the United Housing Foundation and the Trustees of the United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan, held on March 19, 1996 and December 18, 1996.
- United Housing Foundation Project Proposal (Box 1, Folder 35)
- United Housing Foundation By-Laws and Liquidation of Community Services, Inc., 1997 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- United Housing Foundation Memos to the Board of Directors, 1997-2001 (Box 1, Folder 37)
- United Housing Foundation Board of Directors Meeting Minutes, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  Minutes for meetings held on: March 12, 1998; July 15, 1998; November 20, 1998; March 4, 1999; March 22, 1999; April 12, 1999; June 9, 1999
- United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan Trustees Meeting Minutes, 1998-1999 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  Minutes for meetings held on: July 15, 1998; March 22, 1999; June 9, 1999.
- United Housing Foundation Retirement Plan Audits, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  Invoices for audits.
- United Housing Foundation Merger Plan, 2002 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  Plan for merger with the National Rural Electric Cooperative Association (NRECA) Retirement and Security Plan
- United Housing Foundation Dissolution, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 42)
- United Housing Foundation Correspondence, 1996-2001 (Box 1, Folder 43)
- United Housing Foundation - Groundbreakings Plus (Box 2)
  - United Housing Foundation Groundbreakings (Box 2, Folder 1)
    Videos of groundbreaking ceremonies